A Guide to the Papers of Cornelius Hite Fauntleroy 1859-1921
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Cornelius Hite Fauntleroy 1859-1921
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
12825
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
The papers were a gift of Thomas Fauntleroy Ball, 1963 December 6.
Biographical/Historical Information
Cornelius Hite Fauntleroy, lawyer, of St. Louis, Missouri, was born in Winchester, Virginia, 1859 December 31, a son of Thomas Turner and Elizabeth Smith (Hite) Fauntleroy. He pursued his early education in the Shenandoah Valley Academy, at Winchester, Virginia and in 1877 was enrolled among the students of the University of Virginia, where he remained until the summer of 1879. In 1889 he again entered the institution and in 1884 the degree of Master of Arts was conferred upon him. While studying he was also acting as a teacher, being instructor in Greek under Professors Price and Wheeler from 1881 until 1897, when he removed to St. Louis, Missouri, and resumed the practice of law in that city.
Scope and Content Information
The papers of Cornelius Hite Fauntleroy consist of correspondence, including testimonials for Mr. Fauntleroy; newspaper clippings; miscellaneous papers, including notes on the Fontaine family; University of Virginia student absence reports; and, an account of Rebecca B. Marshall's Civil War experiences from her home at "Edgeworth," Fauquier County, Virginia.
Contents List
- Correspondence
  - Thomas R. Price to C.H.F. 1881 Sep 6, ALS
  - John H. White to Davidson College 1883 Apr 4, ALS
  - Thomas R. Price to the Trustees of Davidson College 1883 Apr 4, ALS
  - John H. Wheller to the Trustees of Davidson College, ALS
  - William E. Peters to Davidson College 1883 Apr 9, ALS
  - William E. Peters to C.H.F. 1883 Apr 9, ALS
  - Charles S. Venable to A.D. Hepburn 1883 Apr 12, ALS
  - Maximilian Schele De Vere to C.H.F. 1883 Apr 19, ALS
  - copies of several letters ca. 1883, ALSs
  - Maximilian Schele DeVere to C.H.F. 1883 Apr [?], ALS
  - C.H.F. to the Trustees of Davidson College 1883 May 1, ALS
  - William J. Bingham to the Trustees of Davidson College; with enclosure, B. Johnson Barbour to the Trustees of Davidson College 1883 May 2,3, 2 ALSs
  - William E. Peters to John R. Sampson 1883 June 12, 14 (2), 3 ALSs
  - W. J. Marton to C.H.F. 1883 Jun 25, ALS
  - John R. Sampson to C.H.F. 1883 Jul 3
- Miscellaneous
  - copy of resolution of Elizabeth City County and Hampton town 1775 Nov 23, TMs
  - University of Virginia absence reports 1878 Apr 1- 1879 Jul 5, 3 items
  - Newspaper clippings 1898-1961, n.d.
  - During our Civil War ..., by Rebecca B. Marshal n.d., TMs
  - Fontaine family, notes n.d.